Guide to the Federal Theatre Project playscript and radioscript collection, 1930s
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Federal Theatre Project playscript and radioscript collection
1930s
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Federal Theatre Project
C0002
36 linear ft.
The Federal Theatre Project Playscript and Radioscript Collection contains over 200 copied playscripts and radioscripts, written and performed in the 1930s for the Federal Theatre Project.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Federal Theatre Project.
Historical Information
The Federal Theatre Project was a division of the Works Progress Administration (WPA), which provided employment for large numbers of artists, writers, and performers during the Great Depression (1929-1939). The Federal Theatre began in 1935 and, until its end in 1939, flourished as the first and only federally sponsored and subsidized theater program in the United States. Directed by Hallie Flanagan (1880-1969), it was a way for theatrical professionals to gain employment during the Depression. Jobs were provided for many people, including actors, playwrights, scene designers, scene builders, seamstresses, lighting experts, ushers, box-office men, and stagehands.
Like many New Deal programs implemented by President Franklin D. Roosevelt, the Federal Theatre Project was intended not only to benefit its participants, but also to enrich the condition of the nation. Theater was a distinguished part of American popular culture, but the economic downturn of the Depression had bankrupted the entire theater industry. As the theater houses closed down, the nation was left without an outlet for theatrical creativity. According to Hallie Flanagan, this hurt the nation as much as it hurt the theater industry - indeed, the nation was their audience and the theater could provide entertaining distractions from the effects of Depression as well as offer commentary on present conditions.
But it was not enough to simply return to the pre-Depression concept of theater. In the first meeting her staff Flanagan expressed her willingness to follow Roosevelt's experimental approach to public policy: "In a changing world, a world of experiment, the stage too must experiment - with ideas, with the psychological relationship of men and women, with color and light.... The theatre must grow up."
Flanagan pursued her ideal of developing the relationship between the Federal Theatre and the federal government: "Any theatre sponsored by the government of the United States should do no plays of a cheap, trivial, outworn or vulgar nature, but only such plays as the Government can stand proudly behind in a planned theatrical program, national in scope, regional in emphasis, and American in democratic attitude." To Flanagan, it was imperative that this new theater should be progressive and experimental, yet within a patriotic and informative framework.
The productions that best embodied Flanagan's views on theater were the Living Newspapers. These hard-hitting, poignant plays dealt with contemporary factual material, dramatizing issues such as housing, agriculture, labor, and destitution. Always ending on an upbeat note, Living Newspapers underscored the importance of hard work and morality in overcoming difficult times. Living Newspaper titles include: Triple A Plowed Under, Injunction Granted, One Third of a Nation, and Spirocheta.
The Federal Theatre was noted for employing black Americans at a time when the Federal Government did not actively protect the rights of minorities. The "Negro Theater" (as it was called in the 1930s) was an established industry before the Depression, and it greatly contributed to the success of the Federal Theatre Project. Some of the most spectacular productions were put on by black theater professionals, for example: Macbeth, Haiti, Turpentine, Run Little Chillun, and The Trial of Dr. Beck.
Scope and Content
The Federal Theatre Project Playscript and Radioscript Collection contains over 200 copied playscripts and radioscripts, written and performed in the 1930s for the Federal Theatre Project. Also included is a collection of 62 copied Federal Theatre programs, handbills given to the audience at the beginning of a production. There is also a copy of The Flexible Stage, a book by Emmet Lavery about the history of the Federal Theatre Project. And there are the works of several noted authors in the collection, including Upton Sinclair, Orson Welles, Sinclair Lewis, Arthur Arent, and Langston Hughes.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds the Federal Theatre Project collection, which includes numerous personal and organizational records as well as oral histories.
Alternative Form Available
The scripts are also available as a series in the.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
Theater--United States--History--20th century.
Contents List
- Federal Theatre Project Playscript and Radioscript Collection
  - Playscripts
    - Federal Theatre Project Programs A-Z (Folder 1, Box 1)
      Adelante, Battle Hymn, Beyond the Horizon, Big Blow, Black Empire, Both Your Houses, Children's Autum Festival, Class of '29, Cradle Will Rock, Dance of Death, The Devil Passes, Dr. Faustus, Emperor's New Clothes, Fantacy 1929, Frankie and Jonny, Fly Away Home, Green Grow the Lilacs, Hell Bent for Heaven, Help Yourself, Horse Eats Hat, How Long Brethren, Doris Humphrey-Charles Weidman Dance Program, It Can't Happen Here, Jonny Johnson, Judgement Day, Justice, Like Falling Leaves, The Lonely Man, Long Voyage Home, Madame X, The Man-The Tree, Merchant of Venice, The Milky Way, Night Must Fall, O Say Can You Sing, One Sunday Afternoon, One-Third of a Nation, Outward Bound, Pinocchio, Power, Prologue to Glory, Persuit of Happiness, Ready!Aim!Fire!, Redemption, Revolt of the Beavers, Sing for Your Supper, Six Characters in Search of an Author, Spirochete, Story of Ferdinand, Sun and I, Sun Rises in the West, Swing Parade, Taming of the Shrew, Theatre of the Southwest, Trojan Incident, Twelfth Night, Twilight of the Theatre, When Knighthood Was in Flower, Young Choreographers Laboratory, Young Tramps
    - $595 F.O.B. (Folder 2, Box 1)
      by George H. Corey
    - $595 F.O.B. (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - 1935 January 1938 (Folder 4, Box 1)
      by Arthur Arent; A Living Newspaper Play
    - The Abyss (Folder 5, Box 1)
      by John Wiley; Suggested by a Story of Edgar Allen Poe's
    - The Affairs of a Professor (Folder 6, Box 1)
      by Virginia Yetes
    - Altars of Steel (Folder 7, Box 1)
      by Thomas Hall-Rogers
    - Altars of Steel (Folder 8, Box 1)
    - America February 1936 (Folder 9, Box 1)
      A Peace Pageant for All Grades; The Catholic School Journal
    - America, America! 1934 (Folder 10, Box 1)
      by Alfred Kreymborg; A Mass Recital
    - Angelo Herndon Jones (Folder 11, Box 1)
      by Langston Hughes; A One-Act Play of Negro Life
    - As Thousands Jeer (Folder 12, Box 1)
      by Ben Heck and Eugene O'Heel; With a smirk at Irving Berlin and Moss Hart
    - The Bad Man (Folder 13, Box 1)
      by Porter Emerson Brown
    - The Ballad of Davy Crockett (Folder 14, Box 1)
      by H. R. Hays
    - Barge Incident (Folder 15, Box 1)
    - Barge Incident (Folder 16, Box 1)
      by Herb Meadow
    - Barge Incident (Folder 17, Box 1)
      by Herb Meadow; A Waterfront Tragedy; play reader reports
    - Battle Hymn 1936 (Folder 18, Box 1)
      by Michael Blankfort and Michael Gold
    - Beauty and the Beast (Folder 19, Box 1)
      by Mary Dirnberger; Dramatized from the familiar fairy tale
    - Beyond Tomorrow (Folder 20, Box 1)
      by John W. Dunn; A play of early Oklahoma life
    - Big Blow November 15, 1938 (Folder 21, Box 1)
      by Theodore Pratt; Dramatized from the Novel by Theodore Pratt
    - Big White Fog (Folder 22, Box 1)
      by Theodore Ward; A Negro Tragedy
    - Black Empire 1932 (Folder 23, Box 1)
      by Christine Ames and Clarke Painter; A Drama
    - Blue-Eyed Black Boy (Folder 24, Box 1)
    - Booker T. Washington (Folder 25, Box 1)
    - Brer Rabbit December 1937 (Folder 26, Box 1)
      by Ruth Comfort Mitchel and Alfred Allen
    - Can You Hear Their Voices? 1931 (Folder 27, Box 1)
      by Hallie Flanagan and Margaret Ellen Clifford; A play of our time; Based on a story by Whittaker Chambers
    - The Case of Philip Lawrence (Folder 28, Box 1)
      by Geo. McEnlee
    - The Chameleon (Folder 29, Box 1)
      by German List Arzubide; Adapted from a story by Anton Chekhov; Translated by Angel Flores
    - Cheat and Swing (Folder 30, Box 1)
      by john Woodworth; A legend... about Belle Starr, Queen of the desperadoes
    - Chisbaohoyo, the Sweetheart of the Corn (Folder 31, Box 1)
      by John W. Dunn
    - A Christmas Carol December 1937 (Folder 32, Box 1)
      by Charles Dickens; Dialogue arranged for Marionetts and Hand Puppets by Alma M. Shaw
    - Cinda (Folder 33, Box 1)
      by H. Jack Bates; A Negro Folk Play
    - Cinderella (Folder 34, Box 1)
      by Rose Carlyn
    - Class of '29 1936 (Folder 35, Box 1)
      by Orrie Lashin and Milo Hastings
    - Class of '29 1936 (Folder 36, Box 1)
    - The Common Glory (Folder 37, Box 1)
      by Paul Green; Music by Kurt Weill; A Legend of American Life
    - The Constitution (Folder 0, Box 2)
      by A. Callen, M. Worthington, and I. Reuben
    - The Constitutional Convention March 1938 (Folder 1, Box 2)
      by Oliver Haserodt
    - The Cradle Will Rock June 15, 1937 (Folder 2, Box 2)
      by Marc Blitzstein
    - Created Equal (Folder 3, Box 2)
      by John Hunter Booth; An American Chronicle
    - Created Equal (Folder 4, Box 2)
    - The Danites in the Sierras (Folder 5, Box 2)
      by Joaquin Miller
    - Dark Harvest (Folder 6, Box 2)
      by Arnold Sundgaard; A History
    - Day in Darkness 1936 (Folder 7, Box 2)
      by George Foss
    - Death Comes Creepin' in the Room (Folder 8, Box 2)
      by Grant Moss
    - The Devil Passes (Folder 9, Box 2)
      by Benn W. Levy; A Religious Comedy
    - Dirt 1937 (Folder 10, Box 2)
      by Don Farran and Ruth Stewart; A Living Newspaper Play
    - Double Door (Folder 11, Box 2)
      by Elizabeth McFadden
    - Down in Egypt's land 1933 (Folder 12, Box 2)
      by Charlotte Kohler
    - Dramatist Guild Contest Play #523 (Folder 13, Box 2)
    - Ethiopia [?] (Folder 14, Box 2)
    - Ethiopia March 1968 (Folder 15, Box 2)
      by Arthur Arent; Th First "Living Newspaper"; from Educational Theatre Journal, v. 10, # 1; Introduction by Dan Isaac
    - Everyman (Folder 16, Box 2)
    - Everywhere I Roam (Folder 17, Box 2)
      by Will T. Goodwin; Working Script
    - The Flexible Stage (Folder 18, Box 2)
      by Emmet Lavery; "This book is a postscript to the history of Federal Theatre as recorded by Hallie Flanagan in Arena, published in December, 1940 by Duell, Sloan and Pearce, New York. It carries on where Arena leaves off and should, consequently, be read as a companion volume to Mrs. Flanagan's book."
    - Frederick Douglass (Folder 19, Box 2)
      by Georgia Douglas Johnson
    - Frederick Douglass (Folder 20, Box 2)
    - G.A.R. of the W.P.A. (Folder 21, Box 2)
    - The Girl of the Golden West (Folder 22, Box 2)
    - Go Down Moses (Folder 23, Box 2)
      by Theodore Browne; Based on the Life and Times of Harriet Tubman
    - Granny Maumee (Folder 24, Box 2)
      by Ridgely Torrence; A Play for the Negro Theatre
    - The Grasshopper (Folder 25, Box 2)
      by Howard Koch; A Comedy of Recent Times
    - A Great American (Folder 26, Box 2)
      by Anna Friedman; A Roosevelt Play
    - The Great American (Folder 27, Box 2)
      by Gertrude Worthington Jeffries
    - The Great American Drama (Folder 28, Box 2)
    - Haiti (Folder 29, Box 2)
    - Haiti March 2, 1938 (Folder 30, Box 2)
    - Hell's Half Acre 1938 (Folder 1, Box 3)
      by Abram Hill
    - Hymn to the Rising Sun (Folder 2, Box 3)
      by Paul Green
    - If Ye Break Faith November 16, 1938 (Folder 3, Box 3)
      by Maria M. Coxe
    - Injunction Granted 1938 (Folder 4, Box 3)
      by the Editorial Staff of the Living Newspaper
    - Injunction Granted 1938 (Folder 5, Box 3)
    - Injunction Granted 1938 (Folder 6, Box 3)
    - Israel in the Kitchen July 1934 (Folder 7, Box 3)
      by Noah Elstein
    - It Can't Happen Here September 18, 1936 (Folder 8, Box 3)
      by John C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis; From the novel by Sinclair Lewis
    - It Can't Happen Here September 18, 1936 (Folder 9, Box 3)
    - It Can't Happen Here September 18, 1936 (Folder 10, Box 3)
    - It Can't Happen Here September 18, 1936 (Folder 11, Box 3)
      by John C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis; From the novel by Sinclair Lewis; #1 Script
    - Jefferson Davis (Folder 12, Box 3)
      by John McGee
    - Jericho 1936 (Folder 13, Box 3)
      by H. L. Fishel
    - Jericho 1936 (Folder 14, Box 3)
    - John Henry: Steel Driving Man (Folder 15, Box 3)
      by Frank B. Wells; Tracking Down a Negro Legend, a Saga
    - Juba (Folder 16, Box 3)
      by Warren Coleman; A Negro Comedy
    - Juba (Folder 17, Box 3)
    - King Cotton (Folder 18, Box 3)
      The Living Newspaper Presents
    - King Cotton (Folder 19, Box 3)
    - Land Grant 1939 (Folder 20, Box 3)
      by T. C. Robinson and Rena M. Vale
    - Land Grant 1939 (Folder 21, Box 3)
    - Liberty Deferred (Folder 22, Box 3)
    - Liberty Deferred (Folder 1, Box 4)
    - Liberty Deferred (Folder 2, Box 4)
    - Life and Death of an American (Folder 3, Box 4)
      by George Sklar
    - Little Black Sambo (Folder 4, Box 4)
      by C. B. Chorpenning
    - Living Newspaper Follies (Folder 5, Box 4)
      by Lawrence and Sylvia Martin
    - Living Newspaper Follies (Folder 6, Box 4)
    - Lucy Stone (Folder 7, Box 4)
      by Maud Wood Park
    - Lysistrata of Aristophanes (Folder 8, Box 4)
      by Theodore Browne; An "African Version"
    - Macbeth (Folder 9, Box 4)
      by William Shakespeare; arranged and staged by Orson Welles; Complete Working Script
    - Macbeth April 14, 1936 (Folder 10, Box 4)
    - Medicine Show May 11, 1939 (Folder 11, Box 4)
    - Medicine Show 1986 (Folder 12, Box 4)
      by Oscar Saul
    - Men at Work (Folder 13, Box 4)
      A Pageant of the New Deal
    - The Mikado (Folder 14, Box 4)
      by W. S. Gilbert; The Town of Titifu
    - Miles Gloriosus (Folder 15, Box 4)
      by Plautus; translated by Clarence P. Bill
    - Milk (Folder 16, Box 4)
    - Miracle at Verdun (Folder 17, Box 4)
      by Hans Chlumberg
    - Mrs Lincoln (Folder 18, Box 4)
      by Ramon Romero; An Historical Play
    - My Country Right or Left 1937 (Folder 19, Box 4)
      by Muriel Fox, Marie Reed, Suzette Telenga, and Jane Whitbread; A Musical Satire
    - The Natural Man (Folder 20, Box 4)
      by Theodore Brown; Based on the Legend of John Henry
    - The New Deal (Folder 21, Box 4)
    - New Deal Prospectors (Folder 22, Box 4)
    - Ninety-Seven Cents December 15, 1937 (Folder 23, Box 4)
      by students of Commonwealth College; Commonwealth College Fortnightly
    - Ohio Doom (Folder 24, Box 4)
      by Harold Igo.
    - One Third of a Nation July 29, 1938 (Folder 25, Box 4)
      by Arthur Arent; A Living Newspsper about Housing
    - Pan America (Folder 26, Box 4)
      by Grace H. Swift; A Pageant
    - Panyared March 14, 1939 (Folder 1, Box 5)
      by Hughes Allison
    - Pinocchio (Folder 2, Box 5)
      adapted by Yasha Frank
    - Poor Little Consumer (Folder 3, Box 5)
      by Robert Russell
    - Power (Folder 4, Box 5)
      Living Newspaper
    - Precious Land (Folder 5, Box 5)
      by Robert Whitehand
    - Private Hicks (Folder 6, Box 5)
      by Albert Maltz; Anti-Fascist Play
    - Processional (Folder 7, Box 5)
      by John Howard Lawson
    - Professor Mamlock (Folder 8, Box 5)
      by Friedrich Wolf
    - The Prompter November 1936 (Folder 9, Box 5)
    - The Prophecy 1933 (Folder 10, Box 5)
      by Claudia Hatch
    - The Red Land (Folder 11, Box 5)
      by Robert Sturgis
    - Return to Death (Folder 12, Box 5)
      by P. Washington Porter; A Tragedy of Negro Life
    - The Revolt of the Beavers (Folder 13, Box 5)
    - The Rise of Silas Lapham (Folder 14, Box 5)
    - Rivers Flood (Folder 15, Box 5)
      by Richard Oliver; A Living Newspaper Play
    - The Rubber Gods (Folder 16, Box 5)
      by Margaret Lesueur and Momodu Johnson; a Drama of Native Africa
    - Run Little Chillun (Folder 17, Box 5)
      by Hall Johnson; Across the River
    - Run Little Chillun (Folder 18, Box 5)
    - Russia (Folder 19, Box 5)
    - Saleslady (Folder 20, Box 5)
      by Upton Sinclair; A Little Play for the White Collar Folks
    - Scenes from our Times (Folder 21, Box 5)
      by Christobel Morley Cordell
    - See America First (Folder 22, Box 5)
      by Phyllis Clare Flannery; A Farce Satire
    - See How They Run (Folder 23, Box 5)
      Dramatist Guild Contest Play #60
    - See How They Run (Folder 24, Box 5)
      by George Savage
    - She Canna Perish 1933 (Folder 25, Box 5)
      by Florence Clothier; A Play of the Labrador Coast
    - She Stoops to Conquer (Folder 26, Box 5)
      by Oliver Goldsmith; The Mistakes of a Night
    - Sing for Your Supper (Folder 27, Box 5)
    - Sit Down Sister! June 1937 (Folder 28, Box 5)
      by Fall River
    - The Sky Will Be Lit Up 1933 (Folder 29, Box 5)
      by Janet Hartman and Hallie Flanagan
    - Snickering Horses (Folder 30, Box 5)
      by Jo Basshe
    - So It Didn't Work (Folder 31, Box 5)
      Joseph Lawrence; A Comedy
    - The Song Story of Our Nation (Folder 32, Box 5)
      by Grace Welsh Lutgen
    - The South (Folder 1, Box 6)
    - The South (Folder 2, Box 6)
    - Spanish Grant November 1938 (Folder 3, Box 6)
      by Eugene Deaderick, Cyrilla P. Lindner, Max Mansbach, Lorin Raker; A Living Newspaper
    - Spirochete 1938 (Folder 4, Box 6)
    - Star Spangled (Folder 5, Box 6)
      by Robert Ardrey; A Comedy
    - Stars and Bars (Folder 6, Box 6)
      by Ward Courtney; a Living Newspaper Play
    - Stars and Bars (Folder 7, Box 6)
    - Stars and Bars (Folder 8, Box 6)
    - St. Louis Woman (Folder 9, Box 6)
      by Countee Cullen and Arna Bontempa
    - Steel (Folder 10, Box 6)
    - Straphanger (Folder 11, Box 6)
      by Otis Chatfield-Taylor
    - Sweet Land (Folder 12, Box 6)
    - Sweet Land (Folder 13, Box 6)
    - Tapestry in Linen July 1937 (Folder 14, Box 6)
      by Shotwell Callvert; a Musical Drama
    - Tapestry in Linen July 1937 (Folder 15, Box 6)
    - The Tailor Becomes a Storekeeper (Folder 16, Box 6)
      by David Pinsky; A Grotesque Comedy
    - The Ten Million (Folder 17, Box 6)
      by William dorsey Blake; A Living Newspaper Play
    - Theodore Roosevelt (Folder 18, Box 6)
      by Florine Schwartz; A Play for Children
    - Theodore Roosevelt - A Great Soldier (Folder 19, Box 6)
      by Anna M. Lutkenhaus
    - They Too Arise (Folder 20, Box 6)
      by Arthur A. Miller
    - They Too Arise (Folder 21, Box 6)
    - They Too Arise (Folder 22, Box 6)
    - Three-Cornered Moon (Folder 23, Box 6)
      by Gertrude Tonkonogy
    - Timber! (Folder 24, Box 6)
      by Myrtly Mary Moss and Burke Ormsby; A play on deforestation and reforestation
    - A Time to Remember 1937 (Folder 25, Box 6)
      by marie Baumer; from the novel by Leane Zugsmith
    - The Torch (Folder 26, Box 6)
      by John Broome
    - The Tower Beyond Tragedy (Folder 27, Box 6)
      by Robinson Jeffers; A Play in Poetic Form
    - Townsend Goes to Town 1939 (Folder 28, Box 6)
      by george Murray and David Pelts; A Living Newspaper on Pensions
    - Treasure island (Folder 29, Box 6)
      by Jules Eckert Goodman
    - The Trial of Dr. Beck December 1938 (Folder 1, Box 7)
    - Trilogy in Black (Folder 2, Box 7)
      by Ward Courtney; The Moon is Steel; Carnival for Bolt; North
    - Triple A Plowed Under (Folder 3, Box 7)
    - Trojan Incident (Folder 4, Box 7)
      Based on homer and Euripides
    - Troll Hill 1933 (Folder 5, Box 7)
      by Eleanor Phelps
    - Troubled Island (Folder 6, Box 7)
      by Langston Hughes
    - Turpentine 1935 (Folder 7, Box 7)
      by J. A. Smith and P. Morell; A folk drama of the Florida Pine woods
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin (Folder 8, Box 7)
      Life Among the Lowly
    - Unto Such Glory (Folder 9, Box 7)
    - Utopia, Ltd. 1935 (Folder 10, Box 7)
      by Eden White; A Rollicking Comedy
    - Waiting for Lefty (Folder 11, Box 7)
    - Waiting for Lefty (Folder 12, Box 7)
      Play Reader Report
    - War (Folder 13, Box 7)
    - War and Taxes (Folder 14, Box 7)
    - War and Taxes (Folder 15, Box 7)
    - Water and Wine 1933 (Folder 16, Box 7)
      by Frances Gordon Strunsky
    - We Live and Laugh Revue 1937 (Folder 17, Box 7)
      translated from the Yiddish by Julius Schmerler and Isidore Edelman
    - We the people (Folder 18, Box 7)
      by Elmer Rice
    - Will Shakespeare (Folder 19, Box 7)
      by Clemence Dane
    - The Women of Destiny 1933 (Folder 20, Box 7)
      by Samuel Jesse Warshawsky
    - The Wreck 1933 (Folder 21, Box 7)
      by Molly Day Thacher
  - Radioscripts
    - 13 - 15 Minute Plays March 1939 (Folder 1, Box 8)
    - American Troubadour hour (Folder 2, Box 8)
    - The Banshee August 24, 1938 (Folder 3, Box 8)
      by maxine Schiel; Mystery Dramas
    - The Case of the Girl with the Dark Eyes October 18, 1938 (Folder 4, Box 8)
      by John Fleming; Mystery Dramas
    - The Case of the Skeleton Hands August 10, 1938 (Folder 5, Box 8)
    - Caves of Aladdin September 20, 1938 (Folder 6, Box 8)
    - Clock on the Mantel September 27, 1938 (Folder 7, Box 8)
      by Jack Barefield; Mystery Dramas
    - The Duchess of Padua November 9, 1937 (Folder 8, Box 8)
      by Oscar Wilde; adapted by Donald Macfarlane; Oscar Wilde Cycle
    - An Enemy of the People July 13, 1937 (Folder 9, Box 8)
      by Hendrik Ibsen; adapted by Harry Goldsmith; Ibsen Cycle
    - Ghosts September 21, 1937 (Folder 10, Box 8)
      by Hendrik Ibsen; Ibsen Cycle
    - The Importance of Being Earnest October 5, 1937 (Folder 11, Box 8)
    - John Gabriel Borkman July 27, 1937 (Folder 12, Box 8)
      by Henrik Ibsen; adapted by Harry Goldsmith; Ibsen Cycle
    - Lefty Peroni August 3, 1938 (Folder 13, Box 8)
      by Georgia Backus; Mystery Dramas
    - Little Eyolf August 31, 1937 (Folder 14, Box 8)
      by Henrik Ibsen; adapted by Donald Macfarlane; Ibsen Cycle
    - The Living Dead Man September 13, 1938 (Folder 15, Box 8)
      by Maxine Schiel; Mystery Dramas
    - The Lonely Man January 19, 1939 (Folder 16, Box 8)
      by Howard Koch; adapted by Lawrence Levey; Federal Theatre of the Air
    - A Matter of Mirrors October 11, 1938 (Folder 17, Box 8)
      by Ben Hawthorne; Mystery Dramas
    - A Mystery of Mountain Manor October 25, 1938 (Folder 18, Box 8)
    - Pillars of Society August 17, 1937 (Folder 19, Box 8)
      by Henrik Ibsen; adapted by Charles Crumpton; Ibsen Cycle
    - Salome November 23, 1937 (Folder 20, Box 8)
      adapted by Lewis W. Moyer; Oscar Wilde Cycle
    - Treasure Island of 1939 1939 (Folder 21, Box 8)
      Audition Program
    - Who Shall Deny It April 16, 1938 (Folder 22, Box 8)
      by Benet Costa
    - The Wild Duck July 6, 1937 (Folder 23, Box 8)
      by Henrik Ibsen; adapted by Georgia Fawcett; Ibsen Cycle
    - The Women of the Day (Folder 24, Box 8)
      by Leo Fontaine; A Radio Series